原创翻译  双语字幕
《超女》前情提要
Previously on Supergirl...
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
奥尔森先生情况稳定了
Mr. Olsen is stable.
谁是直系亲属
Who is the next of kin?
凯莉·奥尔森  詹姆斯的妹妹
I'm Kelly Olsen, James' sister.
翻译     DustD  洗七里  DerbyNinja
假如我们不帮詹姆斯  他会死的
If we don't help him, James is gonna die.
你叫我跟你合作去救他吗
You're asking me to work with you to save him?
翻译     阿p  左左  C·A
我能救你们两个
I can save both you and him.
你必须跟她一模一样
You have to be just like her.
行动  思考都要一样
Move like her, think like her.
校对     肉松  饿得慌
我的血红之女
促进和平  我的儿子
Promote peace, my son.
时间轴    想念Gallifrey的Wholock  三水
如果你不起来战斗  就会失去一切
If you don't stand up and fight, you'll lose everything.
后期     你是不是饿得慌
总监     你是不是饿得慌
那就是我不是个爱好和平的人了
I am not a man of peace.
给我找个真正的美国人
Otis, find me a real American.
找一个有感召力的人
Someone charismatic.
我正好有个人选
I think I know just the guy.
他叫本·洛克伍德
Name's Ben Lockwood.
泰斯马克女士
Miss Tessmacher!
伊芙
Eve.
莉娜
Lena.
她还活着  去叫救护人员来
She's alive. Get the EMTs up here now.
局长  有封信
Director, there's a letter.
是莱克斯·卢瑟的
It's from Lex Luthor.
和她待在一起
Stay with her.
亲爱的莉娜
"Dear Lena,
我希望能说这不是私人恩怨
I wish I could say it wasn't personal
设置间谍  偷取你的研究
planting a spy, stealing your research,
但这就是
but it is."
莱克斯与伊芙·泰斯马克是同伙
Lex was working with Eve Tessmacher.
-我的天  -她也来
- Oh, my God. - She's coming to.
莉娜  你还好吗
Lena, hey, are you okay?
-我想是的  -看着我
- I think so. - Look at me.
艾丽克斯
Alex.
艾丽克斯  我得告诉你莱克斯的事
Alex, I've got to tell you about Lex.
他从监狱逃出来了  他袭击了你
He escaped from prison, he attacked you,
他偷走了你的研究  我们知道
and he stole your research, we know.
不  这不是全部经过
No, that's not the whole story--
别动了
Hey, uh-uh, don't move.
还有  我们知道伊芙是他的间谍
And, yes, we know that Eve was his spy.
是  但是我得告诉你
Yes, but I gotta tell you--
你经历了创伤
You've been through trauma.
所以拜托  试着放松
So, please, just try to relax.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你没必要道歉
You have nothing to apologize for.
超女在找莱克斯  她会找到他的
Supergirl is searching for Lex. She will find him.
我查看了整个南太平洋
I checked the whole South Pacific.
没看到莱克斯和他的直升飞机
No sign of Lex or his helicopter.
卡留我在这里保护地球
Kal left me here to protect Earth
而我让他的仇敌逃走了
and I let his archnemesis slip through my fingers.
莱克斯现在做的一切都是因为我失败了
Everything that Lex does now is because I failed.
我施展个精神网  也许能抓住他
I'm gonna cast a psychic net. I might be able to detect them.
荣恩
J'onn...
J'onn?
荣恩  你没事吧  荣恩
J'onn, are you okay? J'onn!
超 女
第四季 第十七集
谢谢你能救我
Thank you for saving me.
你觉得是怎么回事
Why do you think this happened?
我那天晚上告诉过你
I told you the other night...
我不再是和平的人了
I am no longer a man of peace.
当我夺走曼彻斯特生命时
When I took Manchester's life,
我发觉我已经厌倦试图成为我父亲
I realized that I was done trying to be my father.
既然我已经清楚了我不是谁
But now that I have clarity as to who I am not,
我就不再清楚我是谁
I no longer have clarity as to who I am.
你觉得这导致你失去了能力吗
You think that caused you to lose your powers?
有个关于变形者种族的古老传说
There is an ancient story about a race of shapeshifters
他们的星球被毁灭了
whose planet was destroyed.
他们只好
They had to
不断变形来求生
constantly change shape to survive.
他们这样经过了几个世代
For generations, they did this.
直到一天  他们忘记了自己的真实形态
Until, one day, they forgot their true form...
还有那形态拥有的一切
and all that goes with it.
历史  文化
History, culture,
所有的自我
all sense of self.
他们甚至忘了自己种族的名字
They even forgot the name of their race.
我也是个变形者  卡拉
I am a shapeshifter, too, Kara.
同样的事可能发生在我身上
The same thing could happen to me.
肯定有什么我能做的
There must be something we can do.
我坠落时听到了我父亲的声音
I heard my father's voice when I fell.
他死时  科拉令牌与他在一起
The Staff of K'hollar was with him when he died.
也许我可以用它的能量
Maybe I could use its power
召唤他的灵魂来获取建议
to summon his spirit for counsel.
不
No.
莱克斯还在逃  我要帮你找到他
Lex is out there. I need to help you find him.
不不  你总是在帮助其他人
No, no, you are always helping everyone around you.
现在  你只需要照顾好你自己
Right now, you just need to take care of yourself.
他们这所医院
They dress their patients
给病人穿商务正装的吗
in business attire in this hospital?
真有趣
That's funny.
不  实际上  我差不多一小时前
No, actually, I got a clean bill of health
收到了医生的出院许可  所以...
from the docs about an hour ago, so...
你为什么不通知我
Why didn't you call me?
因为你会想把我带回家
'Cause you'd have wanted to take me home.
自我进来这里之后
And the world has turned upside down
整个世界发生了剧变
since I've been here,
我得开始工作  所以...
so I need to get to work. So...
詹姆斯  你没事吧
James, are you okay?
没事  我很好
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
你中枪了  差点死在手术台上
You were shot. You almost died on the operating table.
听着  这不是断了条腿
Look, this isn't a broken leg.
你需要注意发生的事情
You need to pay attention to what's going on.
凯莉  我说了我没事
Kelly, I said I'm fine.
我是个专门研究创伤的精神医师
I'm a psychologist that specializes in trauma.
这是我的工作
This is my job.
而我的工作是关注《外星人赦免法》的否决
And my job is to cover the Alien Amnesty repeal.
这里有上千个美国人
There are thousands of Americans,
正要被政府夺走他们的权利
the government's trying to take away their rights,
而没人在关注  因为莱克斯跑出来了
and nobody's paying attention because Lex is out there.
我只是需要人们知道时事
I just need to make sure that people know what's going on.
所以我得工作  我等下打给你
So I need to get to work, I'll call you later.
你觉得他们要花多久
How long do you think it's gonna take them
-才能找到莱克斯·卢瑟  -找到莱克斯
- to find Lex Luthor this time? - Find Lex...
不不不  放下手机  儿子
Oh, no, no, no, put your phone down, son.
我们手头的事才是真正的新闻
What we're doing here, this is the real news.
我们在创造历史
We are making history.
洛克伍德先生
Mr. Lockwood,
格兰伯里参议员的办公室来电话了
Senator Granberry's office just called,
您今天能过去一趟吗
can you stop by there today?
告诉她我这就去
Tell her I'll be right there.
怎么样  儿子  想不想听又一个参议员
What do you say, son, you want to watch another senator
告诉你父亲他在如何行善
tell your father how he's doing good work?
确实很酷
It's pretty cool.
启动入侵流程
Breach of protocol.
有人入侵  都小心点
It's a perimeter breach. Stay sharp.
可能是莱克斯·卢瑟
It could be Lex Luthor.
超女
Supergirl?
她想干什么
What does she want?
我忘了这些警报声音这么大
I forgot how loud those were.
全员解除警戒
Everyone, stand down.
我
I, uh...
我带来了甜甜圈和我的帮助
I come offering donuts and my help.
莱克斯通常在逃跑后48小时内发起袭击
Lex usually attacks within the first 48 hours of escaping.
我知道我们有分歧
Now, I know we've had our differences,
但我想我们该联合起来抓住他
but I think we should team up to catch him.
尽管我很喜欢肉桂卷  超女
While I do appreciate a good cinnamon cruller, Supergirl,
总统已命令我们
the President has ordered us
将所有人力重新分配到华盛顿特区
to redirect manpower to Washington, D.C.
作为保全
For security.
以防废除法案后出现动乱
In case of any unrest after the repeal vote.
那谁来找莱克斯
So, who's looking for Lex?
联调局  中情局  法警
FBI, CIA, US Marshals.
海豹突击一队到六队
I believe SEAL Teams one through six.
我们以外的所有人
Everyone but us.
莱克斯和我对战时有超能力
Lex had superpowers when I fought him.
他比以往更危险  他会发起袭击的
He is more dangerous than ever, and he will strike.
或许我能帮助超女
Maybe I can help Supergirl.
有多克斯特工的协助
With support from Agent Dox,
我能边出外勤边指挥特区的行动
I can direct the D.C. Operation from the field.
不  我可以指挥特区的行动
No, I can run point on D.C.,
填补你的空缺
cover where necessary.
你集中精力找到莱克斯
You focus on finding Lex.
别让我后悔帮你
Don't make me regret this.
我一直从空中扫描
I've been doing scans of the skies,
但什么都没发现
but I'm not finding anything.
但大多犯罪组织都有弱点
But most criminal organizations have a weak link.
你说得对
You're right.
伊芙·泰斯马克可在为莱克斯做事
Eve Tessmacher was working with Lex.
莉娜比我们都了解她
Lena knows her better than any of us.
我们去找她谈谈
Let's go talk to her.
莉娜最近饱受折磨
Lena has been through quite the ordeal.
考虑到你们过去闹过矛盾
And given the fact that you two don't have the cleanest history,
我想最好由我去和她谈
I think it's better if I talk to her.
是的
Right.
假如她给了你线索
if she gives you a lead,
按一次这个  我立即赶到
press this once and I'll be there.
按两次  我就知道不要去
You press it twice, I'll know not to come.
尼娅在堡垒
Nia is at the fortress
试着梦到莱克斯的计划是什么
trying to dream up what Lex's plan might be,
但目前还没有结果
but so far nothing.
我们会保持和她的秘密通话
We'll keep a secret communication open with her
说不定她能成功
in case she's successful.
我差点忘了
Oh, oh, I almost forgot.
荣恩想让我把这个还给你
J'onn wanted me to give this back to you.
我不知该怎么形容拿回它意义有多大
I can't tell you how much it means to have this back.
-谢谢  -保管好
- Thank you. - Keep it close.
你永远不知道什么时候会用上
You never know when you might need it.
我们打烊了
We're closed.
你没看到牌子吗
Can't you read the sign?
就挂在门上
It's on the door.
牌子
The sign.
该死的牌子
Damn sign.
写着我们打烊了
It says we're closed!
荣恩  我的孩子
J'onn, my son.
我们简单聊两句  好吗
Let's have a little chat, shall we?
这办公室真棒
This is a very nice office.
让我想起
It reminds me
祖昂佐尔大学的图书馆
of the library at the University of Z'onn Z'orr.
你出现了
You're here.
我不敢相信
I don't believe it.
你不是在试着联系我吗
Weren't you trying to contact me?
是的  但我以为
Yes, but I thought I
或许会听到你的声音  或是
might hear a voice or feel...
感到你的存在  我没想到
a presence, I didn't...
没想到你会真的
think you'd actually...
出现在这
be here.
我就在这
I am.
我好高兴
I'm so glad.
我最近是如此迷失
I've been so lost.
对自己的身份如此困惑
So, so confused about my identity.
我尽力以你为榜样
I, I tried to follow your example.
我真的尽力向你学习了
I really tried to follow.
我钻研神圣符号
I studied the Sacred Symbols,
我建议所有人追求和平
I, I counseled everybody, everybody to be peaceful.
可根本没用
But it just didn't work.
现在我陷入了死路
And, and, now, I'm at an impasse.
求你了  我需要指导
I... please... I need guidance.
我不是来指导你的
That's not why I'm here.
那你为什么出现
Then what, why did you come?
因为你失败了
Because you failed.
你本该成为神圣符号的守护者
You were supposed to be the keeper of the Sacred Symbols.
一个圣贤  和平的人
A holy man, a man of peace,
可你说你不是一个和平的人
but you said you are not a man of peace,
所以我来收走神圣符号
so I've come to take the Symbols back.
假如你拿走神圣符号
If you take the Sacred Symbols,
火星历史会永远消失
Martian history will disappear forever.
真可惜  我现在就要拿走
A shame. I'm taking them now.
不  等等  等等
No wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
你不能拿走
Well, you can't.
它们在我头脑中
They're inside my mind.
不
No.
它们就在桌子上
They're here on the table.
-再见  -不不  等等
- Goodbye. - No, no, wait.
等一下
Wait...
我们中断了废除《外星人赦免法》的报道
We interrupt our coverage of the Alien Amnesty repeal
以报道对追捕莱克斯·卢瑟的最新进展
with an update on the manhunt for Lex Luthor.
有消息称他妹妹莉娜·卢瑟是受害者
Sources say his sister, Lena Luthor, is a victim.
当局昨晚在卢瑟小姐的办公室找到了她
Authorities found Ms. Luthor late last night in her office,
莉娜·卢瑟
卢瑟逃跑的受害者
遭人下药并绑架
drugged and bound.
警方认为莱克斯·卢瑟极其危险
Lex Luthor is considered extremely dangerous
有任何消息都应立即上报
and any information should be immediately reported.
莉娜  我没想到你会来
Lena, I wasn't expecting you.
报道都说你被人迷昏了
All the reports say you were knocked unconscious.
你一直都有偏头痛的问题
You were always prone to migraines.
你的脑袋没事吧
Is your head okay?
少来这套母爱的假面孔
Spare me the concerned mother act.
告诉我莱克斯在哪
Just tell me where Lex is.
你有必要这么情绪化吗
Do you have to be so emotional?
真是令人失望
It's disappointing.
我知道你不爽莱克斯比你聪明
I know you're upset that Lex outsmarted you.
他伤了你弱小的心灵
He hurt your poor little heart.
但至少我还有人心
Well, at least, I have a heart.
一个被夸大的器官而已
An overrated organ.
你比假笑的伊芙·泰斯马克好不了多少
You're no better than simpering Eve Tessmacher
她像个迷妹一样满世界追逐莱克斯
chasing Lex like a lovesick puppy.
伊芙爱上莱克斯了吗
So Eve is in love with Lex.
你哥哥给了你所有的机会跟他合作
Your brother gave you every opportunity to work with him.
回到这个阵营里  但你却拒绝了他
To come back into the fold, and you turned him down.
我绝不会跟你和莱克斯站在同一个阵营
I will never be on the same side as you and Lex.
当然不会
Of course not.
你只会和你的朋友统一阵营
The only side you'll ever be on is the side of your friends.
丹弗斯姐妹
The Danvers sisters,
和吉米·奥尔森
Jimmy Olsen.
如果你的这些好友们
Oh, what those besties would think
知道你一直在做什么  他们会怎么想呢
if they knew what you've really been up to.
我只能想到你们的友情会破裂
I can only imagine what went down.
帮了莱克斯几个星期
Weeks helping Lex.
重制你声称会拯救人类的药物
Recrafting the drug you claimed would save humanity.
结果却救了他
To save him.
你们俩并肩合作
The two of you working side by side.
我能察觉到你的恐惧  莉娜
I can smell your fear, Lena.
你会竭尽全力确保你的朋友
Doing everything in your power to make sure
永远不会发现你同谋的事
your friends never find out your complicity.
他们会恨你
They would hate you.
然后你就会发现自己再一次
And then you'd find yourself utterly alone.
孤单一人
Again.
来看你简直是愚蠢
This is foolish.
你什么也不知道
You don't know anything.
因为莱克斯已经抛弃你了
Because Lex has deserted you.
虽然我身陷囹圄
I may be in prison,
但遭人抛弃的不止我一个
but I'm not the one who's going to be deserted.
你回来了
Hey, there you are.
我去医院找你
I went to look for you at the hospital,
但他们说你已经走了
but they said you already left.
我好多了
I got better.
联调局不是已经盘问过了吗
I thought the FBI had already gone through this.
你对我的看法改变了吗
Have you changed your mind about me?
当然没有
No, of course not.
我是来找你帮忙的
I came to ask for your help.
对不起
I'm sorry.
今天太累了
It's been a day.
我的任务是追查莱克斯的下落
Well, I have been tasked with tracking down Lex.
我想问问你有关伊芙·泰斯马克的事
And I'd like to ask you about Eve Tessmacher.
你要利用伊芙去抓莱克斯
You're gonna use Eve to get to Lex.
我认为她就是突破口
I think she's the weak link.
我想参与这次调查
I want in on the investigation.
莉娜  你刚刚才遭人袭击
Lena, you were just assaulted.
虽然我不是警察  但我了解伊芙
Yeah, and I'm not a cop, but I know Eve.
好吧
Okay.
但你该知道我和超女连手找莱克斯
But you should know that I'm working with Supergirl on this.
比我们之间所存在的分歧都更重要
Finding Lex is more important than any differences we may have.
-没错  -我有头绪了
- Yeah. - I know just where to start.
这就是我们的小队
So this is the team.
没错  莉娜刚加入我们
Yes, Lena has joined us.
我们为什么来郊区
Uh, so why are we in 'burbs?
我发现伊芙爱上了莱克斯
Well, I realized that Eve is in love with Lex.
莱克斯的疯子女友
Crazy Lex-girlfriend.
这说明她会随心所动
Which indicates her heart drives her actions.
她提到过一位年长的姑姑
And she spoke fondly of an elderly aunt,
是她在市里唯一的亲人
her only family in the city.
玛丽·泰斯马克
Mary Tessmacher.
这是她家
This is her house.
伊芙每周日都会来看她
Eve used to visit every Sunday.
所以伊芙也许和她还有联系
So Eve might still be in contact with her.
很好的线索
Good lead.
有什么能帮到你们的吗
Can I help you ladies?
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
格兰伯里参议员  很高兴见到你
Senator Granberry, good to see you.
谢谢你来
Thanks for coming.
这就是你儿子吧
This is your son.
我叫乔治·洛克伍德  女士
George Lockwood, ma'am.
我刚刚给他介绍了一下
I was just giving him an intro
华盛顿这里是怎么处理事务的
on how things get done in Washington.
其实  我们刚刚在聊
As a matter of fact, we were just talking about
这次废除进展得更快
how this repeal is moving even faster
快过当年的《宅地法案》...
than the Homestead Act of...
1862年的
1862.
我改变主意了
I've changed my mind.
我不会投废除同意票
I'm not voting for the repeal.
你说什么  什么
Excuse me? What?
好吧
Okay.
但如果
But if...
如果你投反对票  你的街道也会投反对票
If you vote no, then your block's gonna vote no,
那就是八票反对  我们就输了
and that's eight votes we'll lose.
如果我们突然剥夺了强大外星人的权利
If we suddenly strip rights from powerful aliens,
他们会作何反应呢
how are they gonna react?
反应会过激
Badly.
如果他们抗议  反抗  战争就会爆发
If they protest, revolt, and we have a war on our hands,
这对人类不好
then that is bad for humans.
我理解  你在害怕
I understand, you're acting out of fear.
但是也许你应该害怕普通大众
But maybe, just maybe you should fear the common man.
自由代表那一套也许在你的地盘行得通
Agent Liberty may play to your steel town base,
但在这里不行
but not here.
欢迎来到华盛顿
Welcome to Washington.
你醒了
You're awake.
你还在这里
You're still here.
这怎么可能呢
How is this even possible?
我留下来只是因为你晕过去了
I only stayed because you fainted.
既然你现在已经恢复意识
Now that you've regained consciousness,
我就走了
I'm going.
等等  你不能就这样离开
Wait, you can't just leave.
我们经历了这么多
After everything we went through,
你把符号传给了我...
for you to pass the Symbols onto me--
你可以想象  在你选择暴力时
You can imagine how disappointed I was
我有多失望
when you resorted to violence.
所以我才想联系你
That's why I was trying to contact you.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我想...
I'm trying to...
我想搞清楚我到底应该成为什么样的人
I'm trying to figure out who I'm supposed to be.
这是世界上最简单的问题
The easiest question in the world.
答案是什么
What's the answer?
你吗
For you?
我不知道
No idea.
你自己去想
You figure it out.
我寻求你的帮助  可你出现之后
I ask you for help and all you do
却让事情恶化了
is turn up and you make it worse.
我是最后一个绿火星人
I'm the last Green Martian.
如果我失去自我
If I lose myself,
我们不仅会失去火星信仰
we not only lose Martian religion,
还会失去一切
we lose everything.
我们全部的历史
Our entire history.
你给我的所有记忆
Every memory you ever gave me.
我的妻子
My wife.
我的女儿们
My daughters.
所以事情很紧急
So this is urgent.
对
Yeah.
非常紧急
Oh, yeah.
我知道这个问题该如何解决
I know what will solve this problem.
什么  是什么
What? What? What?
一杯好喝的热"咖灰"
A nice hot cup of c'off'ee.
什么
What?
我留下喝一杯吧
I'll stay for one.
玛丽在佛罗里达州晒太阳
Oh, Mary's in Florida soaking up the rays,
而我却枯坐在这里
and I'm plant sitting.
玛丽是惹上什么麻烦了吗
Is Mary in some kind of trouble?
完全没有
No, uh, not at all.
我们来这里是因为她的侄女  伊芙
We're just here because of her niece, Eve.
你认识她吗
Do you know her?
家庭聚会时我最爱她  还是最佳保龄球友
Well, she's my favorite cousin and bowling bud at the family reunion.
她不可能真的跟莱克斯·卢瑟有关系
There's no way she's really involved with that Lex Luthor.
-他太奇怪了  -你叫什么名字
- He's a creeper. - What was your name again?
比茜  草字头茜
Bitsie, with an I-E.
你有女儿吗  比茜
Do you have any daughters, Bitsie?
有  双胞胎
Yes, twins.
在参加夏令营
They're at camp.
我好想念那两个小家伙
I miss those little chipmunks.
你上次见到伊芙是什么时候
When was the last time you saw Eve?
几个月前
Months ago.
除非在新闻里
Oh, unless you count seeing
看见她一闪而过的马克杯也算
her gorgeous mug splashed across the news.
她经常说为你工作有多么好  卢瑟女士
She always said how amazing it was to work for you, Ms. Luthor.
你之前有不舒服吗  比茜
Were you sick at all, Bitsie?
我吗  我健康得很  怎么了
Me? Healthy as a horse. Why?
只是伊芙说过她有一位表亲
Uh, just something Eve said about a cousin
得了癌症  还有两个女儿
with cancer who had two daughters.
我的血橙蛋糕  来一点吗
My blood orange cake. Want some?
我永远无法拒绝蛋糕
I can never turn down cake.
她在撒谎
She's lying.
她的心跳都快赶上蜂鸟了
Her heart's as fast as a hummingbird's.
是啊  我也这么觉得
Yeah, I think so too.
比茜  你的手
Uh, Bitsie, your... Your hands.
你的手应该会被烫伤  但是甚至都没发红
Your hands should be scalded, they're not even red.
你之前病了
You were sick.
还去了临终赡养院
You were on hospice.
伊芙用我给詹姆斯制作的血清治好了你
Eve cured you with the serum I made for James.
她来过这里
She was here.
我要你们离开我姑姑的房子
I want you out of my aunt's house!
我常喝牛奶身体好
I drink a lot of milk?
-放下刀  -你不能抢走它
- Drop it. - You can't take it out of me.
我不想再生病了
I don't want to be sick again.
没事的  没关系
It's okay. It's okay.
我们不是来伤害你的
Hey, we are not here to hurt you.
伊芙救了我  她是好人
Eve saved me. She's good.
我明白
I hear you.
但如果世界都看错了伊芙
But if the world is wrong about Eve,
那你就告诉我们真相
then tell us what's right.
伊芙在逃离你们和警方追捕时来了这里
Eve came here when she was on the run from you and the police.
她冒着被抓的风险来帮我
She risked getting caught to help me.
她为你做了一件好事
She did a good thing for you.
但她跟莱克斯待的时间越久  问题就会越严重
But the longer she's with Lex, the more trouble she's in,
危险也会更多
and the more danger.
帮我们找到她
Help us find her.
我不知道她去了哪里
I don't know where she went.
但我知道
But I know she used to
她以前在纳欣诺市大学一家实验室工作
work out of a lab at National City University.
伊芙有秘密实验室吗
Eve had a secret lab?
看来伊芙的秘密有很多
Seems there are a lot of things about Eve that were secret.
这边
This way...
等你收到信号时
Okay, when you get the signal,
就往那个方向走900米
go that way exactly 900 meters.
我的英文比你说得好
I speak English better than you.
无所谓  这又不是比赛
Whatever. It's not a contest.
你先穿上这个
And put this on first.
什么
What?
你看起来跟她一模一样
You really look exactly like her.
这个办公室里能放十个我的公寓
I could fit ten of my apartments into this office.
是啊  不错吧
Yeah, it's not bad, huh?
你手里是什么
What you got there?
创伤后心理医生的转诊文件
Referrals for post-trauma psychologists.
都在纳欣诺市
All in National City.
拜托  听着...
Come on. Come, look...
凯莉  我说过了  我不需要帮助
Look, Kelly, I told you, I don't need help.
我不需要帮助
I don't need help.
詹姆斯  莱克斯试图杀你八次了
James, Lex tried to kill you eight times.
你能不能就听我这一次
If you would just listen to me for once in your life,
这跟莱克斯没关系
maybe you would realize this has nothing to do with Lex.
詹姆斯  你墙上都是电视  但都被你关了
James, you have a wall full of televisions and they're all off.
因为你知道如果打开的话
Because you know that if you turn them on,
你就会看到莱克斯的脸盯着你
you'll see Lex's face staring back at you.
-是吗  -你怕它触发你的记忆
- Oh, is that right? - You are avoiding a trigger.
莱克斯最初追杀我
Lex came after me in the first place
是为了接触到
to get to Superman
不在地球上的超人
who's off planet.
曼彻斯特·布莱克开枪射了我  现在已经死了
Manchester Black shot me, who's dead now,
所以我现在没有危险  谢谢
so I'm no longer in danger, thank you.
但你现在易怒  暴躁  容易出汗
But you are irritable, jumpy, sweaty,
这些都是对触发的心理反应
all psychological responses to triggers.
这还只是我看到的症状
And those are just the symptoms that I can see.
希望你没有再想起来
God forbid you have a flashback.
因为我知道你肯定不会告诉我
'Cause I know you'd never tell me.
知道吗
You know,
不是只有你一个人会分析事情  凯莉
you're not the only one who can analyze things, Kelly.
只有我在医院的时候
The only times that you've come to visit me
你才来看了我几次
are when I was in the hospital.
因为我很虚弱  会听你话  对吗
Because I was weak and you could tell me what to do, right?
詹姆斯  我只是想帮你
James, I'm just trying to help.
那你就听我的话
Then help me by listen...
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不该...
I should, I...
我只是很忙  应付不过来...
I'm just, I'm busy, I'm overwhelmed, I'm just...
这...
This, this is, uh...
也许你该回家了
This is probably a really good time for you to go home.
纳欣诺市大学
房间到处都是铅
Whole room's lined with lead.
伊芙可能不太爱干凈  但是很聪明
Eve may not have been tidy, but she was smart.
好像也不是很聪明
Maybe not that smart.
这是哈伦·艾尔
That's Harun-El.
是的
Yes. It is.
你还留着?
You kept this?
我妈妈跟你说过它有多危险
My mother told you how dangerous it is.
我没留着
I didn't keep it.
我把之前的给了你妈妈  但我又做一些
I gave your mother what I had, but I made more
想看看它的潜力
so I could realize its potential.
我现在的所有研究都是以此为基础的
All of my current research is based on this.
莱克斯的能力就是这么来的
This is how Lex had powers.
这也是你的研究之一吗
Is that a part of your research, too?
所以我才不想跟你合作
This is why I didn't want to work with you.
因为每次我以为我们关系好起来
Because every time I think things are getting better with us,
你就开始怀疑我的意图
you display an inherent distrust of my intentions.
帮助人类保护自己有什么错
What is so wrong about helping humans protect themselves?
因为这种科技落入莱克斯这样的人手里
Because someone like Lex could get ahold of the technology
可以用来做坏事  而事实就是这样
and use it for evil, which is exactly what happened.
你不顾我们做过的所有好事
You look past all of the good we've done
每次觉得不安就发怒
and see red whenever you feel vulnerable.
莉娜用这个救了阿尔戈
Lena saved Argo with this.
救了小萨
She rescued Sam,
治好了比茜的癌症
she cured Bitsie's cancer,
还救了詹姆斯的命
and she saved James' life.
你说得对
You're right.
-什么  -你说得对
- Excuse me? - You're right.
如果你没做出哈伦·艾尔  詹姆斯就已经死了
If you hadn't made Harun-El, James wouldn't be alive,
你用我做不到的方式救了他
and you saved him in a way I couldn't.
我确实有时候会发怒
I do see red sometimes,
这跟自我或者忠诚
and it's not an ego thing or allegiance,
没有关系
or anything like that.
我感觉肩上扛着世界的重担
I feel the weight of the world on my shoulders.
超人离开了  莱克斯又逍遥法外
And since Superman left, and Lex has been free,
这担子就更重了
it feels a lot heavier.
如果我的敌人变强大了
If my enemies are strengthened,
如果我变弱了哪怕一点点
if I'm weakened in the slightest bit,
我都会输
I could lose.
但我不能...
And I just can't...
我不能输
I can't lose.
对不起  莉娜
I'm sorry, Lena.
谢谢
Thank you.
听到这么说就好
I appreciate that.
这事算过去了
Bygones?
过去了
Bygones.
那答案是什么
So what's the answer?
赫隆米尔救了我  你还要问吗
H'ronmeer save me. This again?
我需要指引  你为什么不肯帮我
I need guidance. Why won't you help me?
我为什么要帮你
Why should I?
没有完成任务的人不是我
I'm not the one who failed at the one task I have.
那是另一个绿火星人
Or was it another Green Martian
清除了超查部上校的记忆
who erased the mind of the DEO colonel,
进入了
who reached into
曼彻斯特·布莱克的脑子里  伤害了他
Manchester Black's brain to inflict pain upon him,
让他进入你的思想
and opened a channel for him to access your mind
好来破坏我的墓地
so he could defile my grave site
偷走它本来可以
and steal the Staff of K'hollar,
用来毁灭地球的科拉令牌
which he could've used to destroy planet Earth?
我做的一切都是为了和平
Everything I did, I did in the name of peace.
-你杀了他  -他是个杀手
- You killed him. - He was a killer.
那么你也是
Then so are you.
那你会让我怎么做
Well, what would you have me do?
整天坐这儿祷告
Sit around and pray all day
任外面的世界毁灭  就像你在火星上那样
while the world around me burns like you did on Mars?
至少我没逃跑
At least I didn't run.
我一直想为此弥补
I have been trying to make up for that.
通过保护这个星球来弥补
By protecting this planet.
尝试了
Trying
又失败了
and failing.
如果我这么失败  你为什么告诉我符号的事
If I'm such a failure, why did you trust me with the Symbols?
因为你说你能处理好
Because you said you could handle it.
你坚持...
You insisted--
我就不应该
I shouldn't have!
我想象你一样  爸爸  但我做不到
I tried to be you, Father, but I can't!
你不应该问我
And you should never have asked me.
我不是一个和平的人
I'm not a man of peace!
如果这意味着我必须放弃这些符号
And if that means I have to give up the Symbols,
火星教也必须灭亡  那就这样吧
and Martian religion has to die, then so be it.
至少我会知道我是谁
At least I will know who I am!
你是谁呢
And who are you?
我是火星猎人
I'm the Martian Manhunter!
对
Yes.
你确实是
You are.
我母亲监狱的设计图
The blueprints to my mother's prison.
伊芙有没有提过一只家庭宠物
Ugh, okay, did Eve ever mention, like, a family pet?
这里
Here.
"我爱莱克斯"
"I love Lex"?
好恶心
Gross.
真的
Truly.
好了  让我们看看伊芙在干什么
All right, let's see what Eve was up to.
这是她的实验日志吗
Is that her experiment log?
看起来像是她在治疗完以后
Looks like she was trying to extract my serum
从别人身上提取我的血清
from someone after treatment.
看看这个
Look at this.
13号卡德摩斯枪
It's a Cadmus-13.
就是詹姆斯挨的那种枪
It's the same type of gun that shot James.
《金属人协议》
Oh, Metallo Protocol.
莱克斯和伊芙在试图使用卡德摩斯的金属人科技
Lex and Eve were trying to use Cadmus' Metallo technology.
看看测试对象表上有谁的名字
And look whose name is on the test subject list.
奥蒂斯·格雷夫斯
Otis Graves.
他们肯定就是这样让他复活的
That must be how they brought him back to life.
他还不是第一个
Well, he wasn't the first one.
看来在他之前还有五个测试失败的对象
Looks like there were five failed test subjects before him.
你觉得他们身上发生了什么
What do you think happened to them?
艾丽克斯  不
Alex, no!
我来分散他的注意力  你赶快跑
I'll distract him and you make a run for it.
不  氪石会杀了你的
No, the Kryptonite will kill you.
我应该带手榴弹的
I should've brought grenades.
我觉得我可以用你的眩晕枪做一个
I think I can make one with some help from your stun gun.
快走
Go!
喂  弗兰肯·贝里
Hey, Franken Berry.
我猜不是甜甜圈
Not donuts, I presume.
不  别动  别动
No, don't, don't.
是一颗氪石心脏
That's a Kryptonite heart.
被用来复活第二个金属人
It was used to reanimate the second Metallo.
还有第一个
And the first.
很可能还有奥蒂斯
And possibly Otis.
比甜甜圈好多了
Much better than donuts.
伊芙·泰斯马克在和奥蒂斯·格雷夫斯合作
Wait, Eve Tessmacher was working with Otis Graves,
奥蒂斯·格雷夫斯又在和自由代表合作  对吗
and Otis Graves was working with Agent Liberty, correct?
所以莱克斯可能和本·洛克伍德有联系
So even Lex might have a connection to Ben Lockwood.
好吧  又扯到传递性了
Well, transitive property strikes again.
我需要和洛克伍德谈谈
I need to have a chat with Lockwood.
看看他跟伊芙和莱克斯有什么联系
See what his connection to Eve and Lex might be.
我去找莉莉安谈
I'll talk to Lillian.
这是我最不想做的事
It's the last thing I wanna do,
但她不久前给了我一些关于奥蒂斯的信息
but she gave me some info on Otis a while ago,
而她知道的事总是比说出来的多
and she always knows more than she says.
你走之前
Before you go,
他们对你在伊芙的实验室
they ran a ballistics test
发现的13号卡德摩斯枪做了弹道检测
on the Cadmus-13 gun you found in Eve's lab.
和射中詹姆斯的子弹完全吻合
It's a definite match to the bullet that shot James.
伊芙开枪打了詹姆斯
Eve shot James?
这意味着莱克斯也是幕后黑手
Which means that Lex was behind this, as well.
可是为什么
But why?
就在你以为伊芙最不可能背叛的时候
Just when you think you've got to the bottom of Eve's betrayal,
情况反而越来越糟
it gets deeper and deeper.
詹姆斯有权知道是谁对他开的枪
James deserves to know who shot him.
还有袭击他的人仍在逃
That his attacker's still out there.
我去华盛顿之前会告诉他
I'll tell him before I go to D.C.
我们会找到伊芙的
We will find Eve.
我保证
I promise.
你故意惹我生气
You tricked me into getting angry.
你已经生气了
You were angry already.
忍下来就好
Just pushing it down.
你对我生气没错  荣恩
And you were right to be angry with me, J'onn,
我没说清楚
I wasn't clear.
我说希望你促进和平
I said I wished for you to promote peace,
但我从来没打算让你成为我
but I never intended for you to become me.
我的意思是无论在什么状况下
I meant only that you should help the world
你都应该帮助这个世界
in whatever state is true to you.
再次找到你的时候
When I found you again,
我为你成为了火星人而感到骄傲
I was so proud of the Martian you had become.
我从来没想让你觉得你必须改变  荣恩
I never meant to make you feel you had to change, J'onn.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我没有给你无条件的爱
I failed to impart my unconditional love for you.
很抱歉我不能
I'm so sorry I couldn't
成为神秘符号的守护者  父亲
be the keeper of the Sacred Symbols, Father.
你能让符号保持更长久的生命力
You were able to keep the Symbols alive a little longer.
这让一个老火星人得到了安慰
That brought comfort to an old Martian.
重要的是
The important thing is,
你知道你是谁
you know who you are.
或许还有别的办法
Maybe there's another way.
赫隆米尔给了我们
H'ronmeer gave us the
托兹沙漠中心的符号
Symbols in the heart of the desert of T'ozz.
我可以把它们还回去
I could return them there.
艰苦的旅程
A hard journey.
如果你成功了  它们就会一直休眠
And if you succeed, they will lie dormant
直到有配得上的人来唤醒它们
until someone worthy comes to claim them.
或许有人会的
Maybe somebody will.
父亲  谢谢你的帮助
Thank you, Father, for all your help.
要知道  荣恩
You know, J'onn,
我只是你对我记忆的延伸
I'm just an extension of your memory of me.
你得到的答案
Any answers you found,
都来自你的内心
they came from inside you.
是的  我知道
Yeah, I know.
但见到你还是很高兴
But it was still really good to see you.
我见到你也很高兴
It was good to see you, too...
火星猎人
Martian Manhunter.
你好
Hey.
对伊芙的追踪怎么样了
How's the hunt for Eve coming?
好吧
Well, um,
我们发现她复活了奥蒂斯
we found out she revived Otis,
然后从她追查到了本·洛克伍德
which connects her to Ben Lockwood,
所以我现在要去华盛顿质问他
so I am going to D.C. now to question him.
所以洛克伍德和卢瑟可能有关系吗
So Lockwood and Luthor may be connected?
我们认为是这样  但
We think. But, uh...
那不是我来找你谈话的原因
That's actually not the reason I came to talk to you.
我们在伊芙的实验室发现一把枪
We found a gun in Eve's lab.
超查部证实枪里的子弹和你体内的相同
The DEO matched the bullets to the one you were shot with.
不是曼彻斯特·布莱克枪击你的  詹姆斯
Manchester Black didn't shoot you, James.
是伊芙干的
It was Eve.
所以莱克斯也是幕后黑手
So that means Lex is behind this, too.
你们看见了吗
Did you see?
《外星人赦免法》刚刚被废除了
The Alien Amnesty Act was just repealed.
什么
What?
废除《外星人赦免法》
...to repeal the Alien Amnesty Act.
我知道有一部分人会很惊讶
I'm sure some of you are surprised,
-但我向你们保证  -伊芙
- but I can assure you... - Eve.
你们看见了吗
Did you see that?
那是伊芙  她现在在华盛顿
That was Eve. She's in D.C.
动作真快
That was quick.
你朋友已经背叛你了吗
Your friends betray you already?
不是的  母亲  我来给你这个
No, Mother. I came to give you this.
监狱的图纸吗
The blueprints to the prison?
-莱克斯来找过你  -真不喜欢说我早说过
- Lex was coming for you. - I hate to say I told you so.
真的吗
Really?
因为我超爱说这句话
'Cause I just love saying it.
看看你的牢房  母亲
Look at your cell, Mother.
看见你的名字了吗  母亲
Do you see your name, Mother?
红色的字  是莱克斯的笔迹
Written in red, in Lex's handwriting.
我们都知道这意味着什么
We both know what that means.
不  他不会
No. He wouldn't.
莱克斯是来找过你
Lex was coming for you.
但不是救你  而是杀你
But not to free you. To murder you.
问题是  母亲
The question is, Mother,
他为什么要来杀你
why would he bother to come and kill you?
除非你知道什么
Unless you knew something.
知道能找到他的线索
Something that could be used to find him?
你要把生命赌在谁身上
So who are you gonna bet your life on?
那个神经病  还是我
The psychopath... or me?
唯一一个有能力有意愿保护你的人
The only person who can or will protect you.
等你准备好了  再告诉我
You can tell me what you know when you're ready.
我很有耐心
I'm patient.
莉娜
Lena.
别走
Wait.
参议员们正在陆续进入
The senators are making their way in now.
在总统到来之前  我们只能拍照片
Until the President arrives, we will only be doing photos.
这里没有伊芙的踪迹
No sign of Eve down here yet.
或许我最好上去看看
Maybe I'd better look up there.
格兰伯里参议员  失陪一下
Senator Granberry, excuse me for a second.
出什么事了
Uh, what happened?
你为什么改了票
Why did you change your vote?
你偷着乐吧
Just take the win.
洛克伍德先生
Mr. Lockwood.
不许提问  奥尔森先生
No questions, Mr. Olsen.
你知道是奥蒂斯·格雷夫斯
You're aware that Otis Graves
协助了莱克斯·卢瑟逃跑  对吧
helped Lex Luthor escape, aren't you?
奥蒂斯·格雷夫斯已经死了
Otis Graves is deceased.
事实上  他没死
Actually, he's not.
我跟莱克斯·卢瑟没任何关系
I have nothing to do with Lex Luthor.
你确定吗
Sure about that?
超女
Supergirl.
你怎么找到我的
How on earth did you find me?
唯一一辆受X射线散射场保护的车吗
The only car protected with an X-ray scatter field?
倒霉
Oh, poo.
给我出来
Out of the car.
等着看好戏吧
Enjoy the show.
-我爸爸  -快走
- My dad. - Come on.
我们走
Let's go.
带她出去
Take her out!
我的天
Oh, my God.
让他们有多恨  就有多怕
Let them hate so long as they fear.
是超女
It was Supergirl.
我的美国同胞们  你们现在一定已经听到
My fellow Americans, by now you have surely heard
我们伟大国家的核心遭受袭击的消息
that the heart of our great nation was attacked...
许多人还相信她会带来安全和希望
by someone many of you trusted with your security and your hopes.
她就是超女
Supergirl.
她攻击是为了报复
She attacked in retaliation
《外星人赦免法》的废除
to the repeal of the Alien Amnesty Act,
她无视我们的民主  只顾她自己
ignoring our democracy in favor of her own
这是野蛮的外星正义
alien brute form of justice.
美国人民欢迎这些外星人
The American people have welcomed these aliens,
他们却以怨报德
they've repaid our hospitality with violence.
但我们并不软弱  我们是美国人
But we are not weak, we are Americans.
我们是人类
We are humans.
为了保护我们  我在此颁布戒严令
I am hereby enacting martial law for our protection.
超女  如果你正在收看  毫无疑问
And, Supergirl, if you are watching, make no mistake,
这一恐怖主义行径绝不会被置之不理
this act of horrific terrorism will not go unanswered.
你现在是头号公敌
You are now public enemy number one.
超女绝不会做出这种事
There's no way Supergirl would do something like this.
我知道
I know.
我错了
I was wrong.
我需要你帮助
I need your help.
你能留下来吗
Think you can stick around?
我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
我是荣恩·荣兹  私家侦探
This is J'onn J'onzz, private investigator.
请留言  我会尽快回复你
Please leave a message and I'll get back to you as soon as I can.
你们叫我来是要逮捕我吗
Did you call me here to arrest me?
我们知道不是你做的
We know you didn't do this.
你绝不会做出这种事
That you would never do something like this.
我们和你同一战线  超女
We're on your side, Supergirl.
我们会查明真相
We're gonna find out the truth.
齐心协力
Together.